

Rasha Jazairi



Professional Summary

Innovative Finance Leader with many years of experience in international corporations in European and Middle Eastern markets. Expert in business partnership in multi-functions cross-border and high-paced organizations. Possessing in-depth knowledge of financial analysis and controlling, business controlling, financial planning and budgeting and processes improvements. Demonstrated ability of tracking actual business results against budgets and plans, building KPls and providing solid advice and support of financial strategies to leadership. A well appreciated mentor and business leader.



Work History

2019-10 -Current

Consultant

Jazairi Consulting, Stockholm, Sweden

- Head of EMEA Accounting at Spotify AB.
- Finance manager for Storytel's branch in UAE (Kitab Sawti FZ LLC).
- Finance manager for real estate startup Houza FZ LLC in UAE.

2018-07 -2019-06

Head of Group CAPEX & asset management

Tele2 AB, Stockholm, Sweden

- Responsible for Tele2 group fixed assets' analysis and life cycle.
- Reviewed and analyzed CapEx and fixed assets' financial forecast (CapEx of 3.6 Bn SEK).
- Partnered with leadership team in digital transformation of CAPEX strategic planning processes on group level.
- Oversaw full-scale implementation of the new CapEx process, resulting in saving more than 120 hours/year.
- Led change management activities associated with the implementation of the new process.
- Managed a team of four culturally diverse employees, fostering inspiring atmosphere to optimize employee performance.
- Introduced cultural intelligence workshops for Asset Management organization and group finance org.

2012-12 -2017-06

Nordics Controller, Manager

GE Capital, Stockholm, Sweden

- Significantly improved strategic financial reporting's' quality & timeliness moving Nordics to top performers in international KPIs.
- Prepared & presented Nordics BS/PL & key financial analysis reporting to Nordics & European leadership teams.
- Identified and implemented strategic process improvements need to secure compliance with regulators.
- Achieved timely integration of Real Estate portfolio & JV into GE Capital's portfolio, constituting to 25% of total portfolio.
- Executed on 5 complex portfolio dispositions worth more than 300MUSD in asset.
- Led simplification initiative of Nordics legal entity structure resulting in 40% savings (13 legal entities liquidated/merged).
- Provided decision making support, advice and partnered with senior leadership with regards to due diligence and strategic sale of GE's product portfolio.
- Saved approx.100 hours/year in account reconciliation process enhancement, enabling efficiency in ways of working.
- Supervised accurate, efficient and compliant completion of monthly, quarterly and annual financial reporting packages per US GAAP.
- Managed a team of ten employees (five in Sweden and five in India).



Address

Kungsholmen, Stockholm

Nationality

Swedish

Birth

1980

Phone

+46-76 722 5850

E-mail

rasha.jazairi@hotmail.com

Linkadlı

www.linkedin.com/in/rasha-jazairi

www

www.rashajazairi.com



Skills

Business partnership



Financial Controlling



Problem solving skills



Process improvement



Corporate finance



Business Controlling



Analytical skills



Budgeting and Forecasting



Finance project management



Leadership



Operational Excellence



2009-01 -2012-11

Finance Manager

MIAK Corp, Vilnius, Lithuania

Managed full-scale financial operations for family business, from bookkeeping to invoicing, AP/AR, financial reporting and analysis, besides contributing with financial advice to overseas business expansion.

2005-11 -2008-12

Senior Controller

Ericsson AB, Damascus, Syria

- Performed complex financial forecast and budget analysis to determine forecasted sales, cost of sales, revenue and net profit.
- Improved internal controls and directed ownership for delivering financial
- Identified cost saving opportunities in operations resulting in annual saving of
- Prepared corporate fiscal and business budget plans of (20MUSD) to help strategically direct business operations and strengthen controls.
- Held a leading role in the leadership team for Ericsson's operations of 85M\$ in Net sales.
- Played a key role in procurement committee's decision-making, enabling high efficiency in cost and quality control.
- Provided financial advice in sales committees, ensuring compliance with embargo trade and regulations.
- A manager for an expanded Finance team of 13 employees (FTE of 60 employees) including HR, IT, procurement and supply functions.
- Led full-scale financial process digitalization and transformation for Jordan and Iraq operations with great focus on enhancing ways of working and change management.
- Drove outsourcing of accounting activities to shared service center.

2005-10

Accounting Manager

Ericsson AB, Damascus, Syria

- Successfully led monthly, quarterly and yearly closing activities.
- Managed a team of three employees to achieve their targets.
- Implemented and monitored compliance with SOX controls with regards to processes, policies, procedures and standards.
- Drove legal entity simplification project for operations in Syria, with saving of
- Actively participated in the preparation of annual finance strategic metrics and KPIs & deviation analysis.



Volunteer Experience

Mentor @ American Chamber of Commerce

2015-10 -2019-06

Mentored and provided guidance to young professionals dealing with career aspirations and worked to improve life choices as a mentor in the American Chamber's mentoring program.



Education

1998-09 -2002-04

2017-09 -

2007-09 -

2008-06

2018-05

Bachelor of Economics: Economics and Business administration

Damascus University - Damascus, Syria

Associate Certified Coach (ACC) By ICF

Coachutbildning AB- Stockholm, Sweden

Leadership Core Curriculum

Ken Blanchard/Ericsson AB- Stockholm, Sweden



Languages

English



Swedish



Arabic



Danish



French



2002-02 -